Band together
Bandslam is a comedy, drama, family film directed by Todd Graff.
A  new kid in town assembles a fledgling rock band — together, they achieve their dreams and
compete against the best in the biggest event of the year, a battle of the bands.
Charlotte Banks, played by Aly Michalka.
Sa5m, played by Vanessa Hudgens.
Will Burton, played by Gaelan Connell.
Ben Wheatly, played by Scott Porter.
Basher Martin, played by Ryan Donowho.
Bug, played by Charlie Saxton.
Bandslam is a 2009 American musical romantic comedy drama film directed
by Todd Graff, who co-wrote the screenplay with Josh A.
Cagan, based on a story by Cagan.
The film stars Aly Michalka in her feature film debut, Vanessa
Hudgens, Gaelan Connell, Scott Porter, and Lisa Kudrow.
The story revolves around Will (Connell) and Charlotte (Michalka), who
form an unlikely bond through their shared love of music.
Assembling a like-minded crew of misfits, the friends form a rock group and
perform in a battle of the bands competition called "Bandslam".
Principal photography took place in Austin, Texas.
During filming, the film underwent multiple title
changes, including Will and Rock On.
Bandslam premiered at the Mann Village Theatre in Westwood, Los Angeles, on August 6, 2009,
and was released in the United States on August 14, by Summit Entertainment.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics,
with many praising the acting and soundtrack.
However, the film was a commercial failure, grossing only $12.2
million worldwide against a $20 million budget.
Insiders panned the film's marketing, which many cited as a primary
reason for the film's underperformance at the box-office.
In a brief cameo appearance, this was David Bowie's final
film appearance before his death in 2016.
The film explores themes of new jersey, musical, battle of the bands, rock band.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.